Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（木吉(きよし)）さあ 練習しようぜ！
Let's practice.
（日向(ひゅうが)）ヤツは—
That guy is weird.
変人
でも恩人
But I owe him.
He's the one who encouraged me to play basketball.
オレをバスケに
誘ってくれたからな
あいつは—
He's the man who created the Seirin High School basketball team.
誠凛(せいりん)高校バスケ部を
創った男だよ
（小金井(こがねい)）久しぶりだな 木吉
Good to see you, Kiyoshi.
Yeah!
（木吉）おう
（日向）おう じゃねーよ
Don't give me that!
なんでユニフォームなんだよ
オマエ！
Why are you wearing your uniform?
I got excited about coming to practice again.
久しぶりの練習で
テンション上がっちまってよ
（火神(かがみ)）うおおおおおっ！
Doesn't he seem especially on edge?
（小金井）あいつ やけに
ピリピリしてない？
（伊月(いづき)）ああ
Yeah.
He's acting like he did when he first joined.
入部したてんときに戻ったみたいだ
He doesn't try to rely on anyone else.
まるで周りに頼ろうとしない
He's playing basketball by himself.
１人でバスケやってやがる
（リコ）どうしちゃったの 火神君
What happened, Kagami?
なあ 火神君
Hey, Kagami.
I want to play soon too,
オレも早く
試合に出たいんだけどさ—
but I don't think it's fair for me to ask to start just because I'm an upperclassman.
上級生だからって—
戻ってすぐ出してくれってのも
横暴だと思うわけさ
だからよ—
So...
勝負してくんね？ ワンオンワン
スタメン賭けて
Why don't we play some one-on-one for the starting position?
What?
Episode 20
I Don't Want To Be
（大坪(おおつぼ)）うっ！
（高尾(たかお)）大坪さん
Otsubo...
Who's Seirin's No. 7?
（高尾）あの… 誠凛の７番って
誰なんスか？
（大坪）７番？
No. 7?
When I went to return some DVDs to our club room,
部室にＤＶＤ戻しに行ったら—
I found an article on Seirin in last year's Basketball Monthly.
去年の月(げつ)バスに
誠凛の記事見つけて…
There was one guy I didn't recognize.
そしたらなんか１人
見慣れないヤツがいたんで
It must be him.
あいつか
あいつ？
Him?
The guy who was Seirin's center last year.
去年 誠凛のセンターだったヤツだ
Their team used to revolve around his and Hyuga's cooperative inside and outside play.
以前あそこは ４番の日向と
そいつの—
外中 ２枚看板のチームだった
For some reason, he didn't show up at the championship league.
なぜか決勝リーグにいなかったが
If he had been there, we probably wouldn't have tripled their score.
もしいたら トリプルスコアの
大敗などなかっただろう
No, we may have even lost.
いや—
ウチの負けもあったかもしれん
What?
去年って黒子(くろこ)と火神いなくて
できたばっかのときじゃねえの？
Last year they didn't have Kuroko or Kagami, and they had only just formed.
Come on, how much credit are you going to give them?
（高尾）またまた
どんだけ買ってんですか
Right, Shin?
なあ 真(しん)ちゃん
って 知るわけねえか
I guess you wouldn't know, huh?
I know him.
（緑間(みどりま)）知っているのだよ
（高尾）えっ？
What?
From middle school.
中学時代
一度対戦しただけだが覚えている
We only played him once, but I remember him.
It was before Kuroko was on the bench,
so he likely doesn't know about him.
黒子はベンチ入り前で
知らないだろうが
So what kind of guy is he?
で どんなヤツ？
It was similar to the recent Touou game.
この間の桐皇(とうおう)戦のときと似ている
In the face of overwhelming odds,
圧倒的な差を前にしても—
just like Kuroko, he refused to give up until the very end.
黒子と同じように
最後まで諦めなかった
Hold on. That doesn't make any sense.
ちょっと待てよ
それ おかしくねえか？
You ended up going to see the championship league!
（高尾）結局
見に行ってたんじゃねえか—
決勝リーグ！
ははは
何が“見たくないのだよ”だ！
"I don't want to see it," my ass!
（緑間）ううっ
家が近かっただけなのだよ
I simply live nearby.
（高尾）遠いだろ！ てか逆だろ
知ってんだぞ！
You live far away!
And in the opposite direction! I know!
He's bigger than me, but he's pretty fast!
（火神）オレよりでかいのに
相当速(はえ)え！
（木吉）高い！ 実際に見ると
確かに とんでもないジャンプ力だ
So high!
His jumps really are unbelievable in person.
Amazing!
（福田(ふくだ)）すげえ
Neither one is budging.
（降旗(ふりはた)）どっちも譲らない
（河原(かわはら)）互角
They're evenly matched?
Kiyoshi really is amazing.
やっぱすげえな 木吉
He hasn't played in a while, but he's doing this well against Kagami.
ブランクあんのに
火神相手にここまで
But Kagami's the one pressuring him.
けど 押してるのはやっぱり火神だ
But what is this?
（日向）でもなんだ
木吉の動きが…
Kiyoshi's movements...
はあ 想像以上にしんどいな
This is harder than I thought it would be.
He broke past him?
（土田(つちだ)）抜いた！
Crap, I responded too slowly!
（木吉）いかん 反応が遅れた
It's not over yet.
まだだ
（木吉）何！？
What?
That's amazing!
すげえ あそこで裏からダンク！？
He dunked it on the other side from there.
Kagami wins!
（河原）火神の勝ちだ！
参った オレの負けだ
You got me. I lost.
約束通り スタメンは君だ
Just like I promised, you can start.
Okay.
（火神）うっす
Hey...
ちょっと…
（火神）じゃあオレ 先上がります
お疲れっス
Well then, I'm going.
Good work.
What are you thinking, Kiyoshi?
何考えてんだよ 木吉
Wow, he really is strong.
いやあ 強いな あいつ
（リコ）でやっ！
アンタが外れてどうすんのよ！
And what are we going to do without you?!
いやあ しょうがねえだろう
It can't be helped.
Saying I haven't been playing isn't much of an excuse.
ブランクなんて
言い訳になんねえし これが実力だ
This is the best I can do.
実力だ じゃねえよ ボケすぎだ
足元見ろ
That's not your best. You're acting too stupid.
Look at your feet!
Those are indoor shoes, you moron!
（日向）それ上履きじゃねえか
ダアホ！
What?
Sheesh...
ったく まさか
わざと負けたんじゃねえだろうな
Don't tell me you lost on purpose.
いっけね
Oh, crap!
It wasn't on purpose?!
素(す)かよ！
Sheesh!
もう！
（テツヤ２号(にごう)）わん！
退院祝い
Congratulations on being released.
サンキュ！
Thanks.
（木吉）それにしても
面白いな あの２人は
Those two really are interesting.
Kuroko and Kagami?
（日向）黒子と火神か？
（木吉）ああ
Yeah.
Kuroko's fine, but Kagami...
黒子はいいけど 火神がな
His play is a lot like the Generation of Miracles.
プレーがまるで
キセキの世代っつうか—
Something's wrong with him.
どうも様子が変だ
そうか？ むしろオレには
逆に見えたけどな
Really? It seemed the other way around to me.
おっ 黒子が？
Kuroko?
That's just what it looked like to me.
（木吉）そう見えたってだけだ
あいつらの悩みっつうか
なんか分かるんだよ
I kind of understand what they're worried about.
I've run up against that wall before.
オレもぶち当たった壁だからさ
ま 雨降って地固まるってな
Well, they say fights solidify friendships.
（日向）固まってねえから
困ってんだけど
We're in trouble because their friendship hasn't solidified!
Then why don't you help them solidify their friendship?
じゃあ 固めるのちょっとは
手伝ってもいいだろ
それも先輩の務めだ
Isn't that an upperclassman's responsibility?
I changed my mind. Give that back.
やっぱ返せ それ
What? I thought this was a gift.
（木吉）え 退院祝いじゃ…
（日向）なんか イラッときた
I'm starting to get pissed.
（木吉）ええ
（日向）返せ 返せよ
What?
Give it back. Give it back!
I don't care if you're one of Tokyo's top four teams.
（徳進選手１）都ベスト４だか
なんだか知らねえが
You guys must think we're a joke.
（徳進選手２）なめたこと
してくれんじゃねえか
Hey, Furihata...
なあ 降旗
オレたち１年だって
そりゃあ試合に出たいさ
Us first years want to play in games.
We even got our uniforms.
ユニフォームも一応もらってるし
Yeah.
けどこれはさ—
But isn't this a little too sudden?
いきなりすぎるよな？
I can't believe all your starters are first years!
（徳進選手１）
スタメン全員 １年とはな！
I'm seriously pissed.
（徳進選手３）
カチンときたぜ マジ
Let's destroy them and send them home.
ボロカスに負かして追い返すぞ！
（徳進選手たち）おう！
Yeah!
What?
Coach, what are you thinking?
（伊月）カントク
これ どういうつもり？
あいつがどうしてもね
１年生の試合も見たいって
He insisted on watching the first years play.
Kiyoshi, what is this?
木吉 何だよ いったい？
明日から３日連続
練習試合を組んだわ
Starting tomorrow, we'll have three consecutive days of practice games.
Practice games?
（伊月）練習試合？
夏休み直前に なんでまた？
Why are we playing again right before summer vacation?
So I know exactly what you guys need to work on.
（リコ）今のみんなの課題を
より明確にするためにね
During summer vacation, you'll all have fun practicing as hard as possible.
そして夏休みは
楽しくみっちり猛練習ってわけよ
Hey, Riko. I have a favor to ask of you.
なあリコ １つ頼みがあんだけど
What?
オレには分かる 木吉の考えが
I know what Kiyoshi is thinking!
We're probably going to lose this game, aren't we?
この試合たぶん負けるでしょ
最近火神は
プレーが自己中になってる
And recently, Kagami's been playing selfishly.
（火神）黒子
（黒子）ん？
Kuroko...
もうオレにパスはしなくていい
You don't have to pass to me any more.
Huh?
But they can't win that way.
けど そんなんじゃ勝てない
That's why you're making them lose on purpose, so he can realize he can't just win on his own, right?
だからわざと負けさせて—
１人強いだけじゃ
勝てないことを教えるつもりだった
I see.
（木吉）なるほど
（小金井）あれっ
Huh?
（木吉）すげえな コガ
That's amazing, Koga.
Wait, but...
（小金井）えっ
いやあ だってさ…
（木吉）まあ なくはないけど—
You're not wrong, but...
Do you think he's so stupid he wouldn't notice if we didn't tell him?
あいつって—
そういうの言わなきゃ
気付かないほど バカなのかな
迷いや悩みは
感じなかったけどな オレには
He didn't seem uncertain or worried to me.
If there's anyone I want to notice something, it's him.
むしろ何かに
気付いてほしいとしたら—
彼のほうだよ
He jumps so high! I can't stop this guy!
（徳進選手３）高(たけ)え！
こんなヤツ止められっこねえよ
Seirin....................................................Tokushin
The first years are doing better than I expected.
（リコ）１年生は
思いのほかやるわね
Kuroko's movements aren't bad either, but...
黒子君の動きも 悪くないけど—
Seirin............................................................Tokushin
Our score is lower than I expected.
思ったよりスコアが伸びてない
Is it because he isn't coordinating with Kagami well?
火神君との連係が
うまくいっていないから？
No, this isn't just because of that.
いや これはそれだけじゃ…
Seirin................................................................................Tokushin
All right!
（誠凛選手たち）よっしゃー
（福田）勝ったぜ
（河原）すごいな
We won! This is amazing!
We beat them!
（河原）勝てたぞ オレたち
（降旗）いや ナイスシュート！
Nice shooting!
What do you think you're doing?
どういうつもりよ
（リコ）急に火神君と
ワンオンワンしたり—
Suddenly challenging Kagami to a one-on-one...
Making only the first years play...
１年だけで試合させたり
Kagami ended up beating them by himself.
結局 火神君１人で勝っちゃうし
What are you planning?
何を たくらんでるのかしら？
Why do you guys keep saying such mean things about me?
なんでみんなそう
人聞きの悪いこと言うかなあ
I only challenged him to a one-on-one to see how our abilities compared, seriously.
ワンオンワンのほうは—
お互いの実力を
知りたかっただけだよ マジで
Then what about today's game?
じゃあ 今日の試合のほうは？
ま あるっちゃある かな
Well, I guess I did have something in mind.
Since I didn't play today, I've got extra energy.
（日向）つーか 試合出てねえから
体力ありあまって しょうがねえし
I guess I'll practice twice as much shooting today.
今日 シューティング倍にすっか
うっし
Um...
（黒子）あの…
I want Kuroko to know
黒子君に
知ってほしくてな
the current limits of his basketball.
今の彼のバスケの限界をさ
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Huh?
いや 限界って
What limits?
What did you say after that?
それよりそのあと 何つった？
ボクはこの先
誠凛の足を引っ張るだけです
Going forward, I will do nothing but hold Seirin back.
So please make Kiyoshi-senpai one of our starters.
だから 木吉先輩を
スタメンにしてください
（木吉）彼のバスケは—
Put positively, his style of basketball utilizes his teammates.
よく言えば
周りを生かすスタイル
ほかの４人次第で
強くも弱くもなる
Depending on the other four, he can be strong or weak.
けど悪く言えば—
But put negatively, he relies on others.
人任せとも言える
In order to break through this wall,
この壁を破るために必要なのは—
今のスタイルを捨てることだ
he needs to abandon his style...
（リコ）捨てる？
Abandon it?
and create a new style of basketball for himself.
（木吉）そして創る
新しい彼のバスケ
You don't often come talk to me, but
ったく—
珍しく 話しかけてきたかと思えば
don't get ahead of yourself, moron!
調子こくな ダアホ！
スタメンから外せだあ？
Replace you as a starter?
ベンチのヤツらのことも考えろよ！
Think of the guys on the bench!
It's not your place to say that!
んなもん オマエが言うな！
I'm the one who'll say that!
言うならこっちから言うわ！
（黒子）でも…
But...
I told you, no.
ダメったらダメだ
When the team first formed, Kiyoshi played as a traditional center.
木吉の創部当初の
スタイルはな—
コテコテのセンターだったんだよ
身長が一番
でかかったっていうのもあるが—
He was taller than the rest of us, but
he was also the only one of us who could do it.
ウチではあいつしか できなかった
けど木吉が一番得意なのは
周りを生かすプレイ—
Kiyoshi was actually best at the role of leading the play through his teammates,
like that of a point guard.
ポイントガードだったんだ
He thought it was best for the team for him to play center too.
チームのために自分がセンターを
やるのがベストだと考えつつも—
Yet he also felt he was limiting himself by playing a position he wasn't meant to play.
本来のポジションでないが故の
限界も感じていた
But one day...
けどある日…
Why don't you play both?
じゃあ両方やれば
That's impossible, Koga!
それは無理だ コガ
ポジションが違いすぎる
The positions are too different.
Huh? Really?
（小金井）えっ？ そうなの
The center is the front line who uses power to fight right under the hoop!
センターは最前線のゴール下で
パワー勝負
ポイントガードは
逆にゴールから一番遠い司令塔だ
In contrast, the point guard is the leader furthest away from the basket!
So, he'll just be our leader under the hoop.
じゃあ ゴール下の
司令塔でいいじゃん
What the hell's that?!
（伊月）なんだそれ
You're right. I don't have to choose one.
そりゃあそうだ
どっちかに決める必要はねえよな
両方やろう
I'll do both.
You and Kiyoshi are different,
（日向）
木吉とオマエは違うけど—
but is that really all you can do?
オマエにできることは
本当にそれだけか？
Well, I can't force you to do anything, so I won't say any more.
ま 無理やり
やらせるもんでもねえし—
これ以上は言わねえ
けど どうしてもダメなら
火神ぐらいには言っとけよ
But if you really don't think you can do it, at least tell Kagami.
He believed in you.
あいつは オマエのこと
信じてたからな
Kuroko's always saved me until now, so I want to put some distance between us for a while.
（火神）今まで黒子には
助けられっぱなしだったんで—
しばらく距離とりたいんです
黒子があのまま
終わるはずないんで—
There's no way Kuroko's stopping now,
so I need to make myself stronger, even if it's only a little.
それまでにオレ自身
少しでも強くなりたいんです
Just how awkward is he?
つーかどんだけ不器用なんだ
あいつは
（黒子）すみません
ありがとうございました
Excuse me. Thank you.
おう もういいのか？
You sure you don't need anything else?
Yes.
（黒子）はい！
（テツヤ２号）わん！
（リコ）だけど—
Abandon it?
捨てるって—
But that's the style Kuroko has honed through trial and error.
あれは 黒子君が試行錯誤の末
身につけたスタイルなのよ
Yeah, that's why he has to abandon it without throwing away his direction...
だから捨てるっても
ベクトルはあくまで変えずに…
No, he should be fine now.
いや もう大丈夫だろ
What?
はぁ…
いいなあ ほんと男子って
Boys are so nice.
（火神）レッグスルーから
右ドライブで１人かわす
From dribbling between the legs, drive to the right and break past one guy.
ここですぐにヘルプが来る
Help will come right away.
ゴール下には降旗が見えてた
I can see Furihata right under the basket.
あとはパス出しゃ いいだけだ
From there I just need to pass.
けど それだけじゃ
ダメなんだ
But it's not enough.
A simple pass here isn't enough
ここで普通に
パス出してるようじゃ—
あいつら
“キセキの世代”には勝てない
to beat the Generation of Miracles.
If their teammates stop me for even a second,
ヘルプに一瞬足止めされるだけで
すぐに立て直してくる
they'll be ready again.
In order to win, even if I can't beat them in a one-on-one,
勝つためには—
ワンオンワンで仮に抜けなくても
崩すか 隙を作るか
I still have to throw them off balance or create an opening.
I have to be strong enough to take them on my own.
オレ１人でも
まず戦えるレベルまで行くんだ！
That's where I have to start.
それができて初めて…
Kagami!
（黒子）火神君
Kuroko...
黒子！
Can I talk to you for a minute?
ちょっと話 いいですか？
What do you want to talk about?
（火神）何だよ 話って
（黒子）すみません
（火神）ん？
I'm sorry.
実はまだ
考えが まとまってません
The truth is, I haven't gotten all my thoughts together yet.
（火神）オイッ！
Hey!
I don't know where to start.
何から話せばいいやら—
Please give me a minute.
少し待ってください
From now? Sheesh.
今からかよ！
ったく
ほら
I've got nothing to do while I wait.
ボーッと待っててもヒマだろうが
At least play against me.
とりあえず相手しろよ
You can think while you play.
やりながら考えろ
よーっし！ 14点目！
All right, my 14th point!
Um, please go easier on me today.
（黒子）あの 今はもう少し
手を抜いてください
考えまとめるどころじゃないです
I can't think like this.
I am going easy on you!
（火神）やってるよ軽く
オマエ弱すぎ！
You're just too weak!
The first time we played was a lot like this too.
そういや初めてやったときも
こんなんだったな
そのあと正体を知ったときは
正直たまげた
When I later found out what you could really do, I was blown away.
しかも…
Not only that, but...
I am a shadow.
（黒子）ボクは影だ
I will be the shadow to your light
君という光の影として
ボクも君を日本一にする
and make you the best player in Japan.
Hey, I've been wondering about something since then.
（火神）なあ あんときから
気になってたことが１つある
Why did you choose me?
なんでオレを選んだんだ？
すみません
Sorry.
ボクは 謝らなくちゃいけません
I have to apologize to you.
I lied.
ボクはウソをついてました
In middle school,
ボクは中学時代—
I received a uniform as the team's sixth man.
シックスマンとして
ユニフォームをもらってました
I know that.
（火神）知ってるよ
You were the trump card of the Generation of Miracles.
“キセキの世代”の
切り札だったんだろ
That's not quite right.
（黒子）それは少し違います
They may have believed in me,
確かに信用されて
いたかもしれません
but they did not trust me.
けど—
信頼されてはいませんでした
いえ—
No, it may be more accurate to say...
もっと正確に言えば—
that they stopped being able to trust me.
信頼されなくなって
いったんです
When I was a first year, I was an unremarkable player.
ボクは１年のときはまだ—
何のとりえもない
ただの選手でした
I joined the bench as the sixth man in my second year.
シックスマンとして
ベンチ入りしたのは ２年からです
Back then, I believe they still trusted me.
そのころはまだ
信頼されていた—
と思います
But as their talents began blossoming like Aomine,
けど 青峰(あおみね)君のように
みんなの才能が開花していくと—
信頼は薄れていきました
they lost their faith in me.
The Generation of Miracles began placing their trust in themselves over everything else.
なぜなら—
彼ら“キセキの世代”が
最も信じるのは—
自分自身になっていったからです
Teiko
If we were one point behind with only a few seconds left in the game,
仮に残り数秒で１点差のような
大事な場面では—
Teiko
they could not pass.
パスはきません
Teiko
They had to do it themselves.
彼らが自分で決めます
Teiko
The truth is, it didn't have to be you.
本当は 火神君でなくても
よかったんです
I was simply using you to force the Generation of Miracles to recognize my style of basketball.
ただ—
“キセキの世代”に
ボクのバスケを—
火神君を利用して
認めさせようとしただけなんです
I was wondering what you might say.
ったく 何を言いだすかと
思えば—
そんなこったろうと思ったよ
I had a feeling it'd probably be this.
ずっと感じてたよ
I've always felt it.
I'm just like them.
そもそもオレとあいつらは同種だ
Even though you had supposedly quit the
“キセキの世代”のバスケを
否定して—
Teiko basketball team because you rejected the style of the Generation of Miracles,
帝光(ていこう)バスケ部を
辞めたはずのオマエが—
こんなオレと なんで組むのか
むしろ合点がいったぜ
I knew why you chose to work with me.
Everyone plays basketball for their own reasons.
バスケやる理由なんて
人それぞれだろ オレは別に…
I'm not any different—
No!
いいえ
（黒子）火神君はもう違います
（火神）ん？
Kagami, you are different.
In all of our games so far, you trusted me.
火神君は信じてくれました
圧倒的な力の前では—
In the face of overwhelming power,
I don't think we can win just by working together.
力を合わせるだけじゃ
勝てねえんじゃねえのか？
Those were not parting words,
あの言葉の真意は
決別じゃなく—
but words meant to make us stop relying on each other and become even stronger.
お互い一度 頼ることをやめて—
より強くなるため—
So we could combine even greater strength to win.
より大きな力を合わせて
勝つために
だから 訂正させてください
Please allow me to correct myself.
I am glad I go to Seirin.
ボクは誠凛に入ってよかった
All our seniors are wonderful people,
先輩はみんな
すばらしい人たちで—
our classmates who work alongside us are all great as well,
一緒に頑張る同級生も
いい人ばかりで—
火神君はボクを信じてくれた
and you trusted me.
I am not Teiko Middle School's sixth man, Kuroko Tetsuya.
ボクは帝光中シックスマン
黒子テツヤじゃない
誠凛高校１年
黒子テツヤです
I am Seirin High first year, Kuroko Tetsuya!
I don't want make someone else the best player in Japan.
自分のために誰かを
日本一にするのではなく—
火神君と—
With you,
and with everyone else, I want to become the best in Japan!
みんなと一緒に
日本一になりたい
That's why I will become even stronger
そのために もっと強くなって—
and defeat the Generation of Miracles!
“キセキの世代”を倒します
That's what I've been meaning to do all along.
つーか オレは最初から
そのつもりだっての
それより また
間違ってんじゃねえか オマエ！
And you got it wrong again!
You don't want to be the best. We're going to be the best!
なりたいじゃねーよ
なるぞ！
はい
Yes.
けどオマエ 強くなるっても
どうするんだよ？
But how are you going to get stronger anyway?
I don't know.
（黒子）分かりません
（火神）オイ！
Hey!
But I will find a way by the Winter Cup.
でも必ず見つけます
ウインターカップまでに
バーカ
You idiot, don't be stupid.
トロいこと言ってんなよ
I'll become stronger too.
オレも強くなる
のんびりしてたら置いてっちまうぞ
If you take too long, I'll leave you behind.
Get stronger soon.
とっとと強くなりやがれ
This winter, show it to me...
そんで冬に見せつけろ
Kuroko's new style of basketball!
新生 黒子のバスケを
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
A summer trip, huh?
（火神）夏合宿か
オレ合宿とか行くの初めてっス
I've never been on a summer trip before.
Taking a trip with everyone is fun.
（木吉）おう いいもんだぞ
みんなで合宿ってのは
What are we doing about food?
（火神）メシとか
どうなるんスかね？ 楽しみっス
I'm so excited.
Yeah, I'm sure it'll have a big impact.
（木吉）おう インパクトあるぞ
きっと
Episode 21
Let's Get Started
What? I'm talking about food.
（火神）えっ？ メシっスよ